articles.org 2009-10-04

# Articles.org: Privacy Policy

Articles.org collects personal information from a variety of sources, including from members of the public, advertisers, prospective employees, mailing lists, recruitment agencies, contractors and business partners. 

In general, the personal information Articles.org collects includes (but is not limited to) name, address, contact details, gender, occupation, in some cases membership of professional associations and, where relevant, financial information, including credit card information, banking details and income information. 

**Personal Information you provide:** We store the personal information you enter on the Articles.org website or give to Articles.org in other ways. We obtain most personal information through the posting of ads or discussion forums via the Articles.org website. You may provide information when you request or acquire a product or service from Articles.org or its related companies, provide a product or service to Articles.org, complete a survey or questionnaire, enter a competition, participate in forums or when you communicate with Articles.org by e-mail, telephone or in writing (for example if you contact customer service or provide feedback). 

**Automatic collection:** Cookies: We may use a feature of your browser called a cookie to assign your computer a 'User ID'. Cookies do not contain information by which Articles.org can identify you. They identify your computer to our servers. You may configure your browser so that you are notified before a cookie is downloaded or so that your browser does not accept cookies. Articles.org may use information contained in cookies to make assumptions about the user of the computer and to provide users of that computer with focused advertising which Articles.org believes may be of interest, based on that information. To disable your cookies, please refer to the help menu within your Internet browser. 

**Indirect collection:** Articles.org endeavours to collect personal information about an individual only from that individual. In some circumstances Articles.org may obtain personal information from a third party. If you provide personal information about another person to Articles.org, Articles.org requires that you inform that person you have done so and provide them with a copy of this policy. 

**How Articles.org uses the information you provide**

Articles.org may use information it collects from you for the primary purpose for which it is collected and for such other secondary purposes that are related to the primary purpose of collection. 

Articles.org generally uses personal information to: 

provide you with products or services you have requested personalise and customise your experiences on the Articles.org website; help Articles.org manage and enhance its services; communicate with you; provide you with ongoing information about opportunities on the Articles.org website in which Articles.org believes you may be interested; give you the opportunity from time to time to receive e-mail from Articles.org. 

If you do not provide Articles.org with that information, Articles.org will not be able to provide you with the requested product or service. 

**Disclosure**

Articles.org may disclose personal information to other companies in the Articles.org which may only use it as set out above. 

Articles.org may also provide your information to: third parties engaged by Articles.org to perform functions on its behalf, such as processing credit card information, mailouts, debt collection, marketing, research and advertising; third parties authorised by you to receive information held by Articles.org; 

If Articles.org sells part of its business, personal information may be part of the assets transferred to the purchaser. 

The Articles.org Network contains features where you are invited to send personal information to organisations other than Articles.org. The choice to send such information to these organisations is entirely yours. You should be aware that any such information you choose to send will not be bound by this policy. 

**How Articles.org treats sensitive information**

**"Sensitive Information"** means information relating to a person's racial or ethnic origin, membership of political bodies, religion, membership of a trade union or professional or trade association, sexual preferences, criminal record and health. 

Articles.org may use and disclose Sensitive Information only for the purpose for which it was provided or a directly related secondary purpose or as allowed by law unless you have agreed otherwise. 

**Management and security of personal information**

Articles.org protects the personal information Articles.org holds from misuse, loss, unauthorised access, modification or disclosure by various means including firewalls, pass word access, secure servers and encryption of credit card transactions. 

**Updating personal information**

Articles.org endeavours to ensure that the personal information it holds is accurate, complete and up-to-date. 

You can generally update personal information that is not membership information on the Articles.org website where you submitted that information. Otherwise, please contact Articles.org on [privacy@Articles.org](mailto:privacy@Articles.org) Where personal information is no longer required by Articles.org, it will be destroyed or de-identified. 

**Seeking access to the personal information Articles.org holds about you**

You have the right to seek access the personal information held about you and to advise Articles.org of any inaccuracy. There are some exceptions to this right set out in the Privacy Act. 

If you make an access request, Articles.org will ask you to verify your identity and specify what information you require. Articles.org may charge a fee to cover the costs of meeting your request.
